YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 6. Program: Series IV. Constituent Groups
Sophia Smith Collection
Groups for "Home Women" started forming in Community YWCAs soon after World War II to provide companionship, adult education, recreation, and a "day out." They were recognized nationally as YW-Wives at the Convention in 1949. As declining participation in the Employed Women's Councils threatened their continued existence, the Employed Women and YW-Wives agreed at Convention in 1955 to try working together for the next triennium. The Young Adult Assembly emerged as "a new opportunity for all young adults to have a national voice." The group encompassed employed women, wives, and young women in YWCA residences, classes, and interest groups, but did not include College Students or Teenagers. The group adopted objectives at its National Young Adult Assembly in 1958.
As the post-war baby boom generation approached its teens, the National Association became concerned with how few of them were involved in the YWCA. It resolved at Convention in 1961 to place increasing emphasis on its work with teens and young adults.
Once again working to adapt the Association to the girl, rather than the girl to the Association, staff searched for appropriate and effective ways to structure programs for the new generation. The constituency was re-defined as encompassing 17 to 25 year olds, and groups were organized in a variety of ways, sometimes just for employed women, sometimes for the entire constituency, sometimes coeducational, and sometimes single sex.
The concerns of the group evolved as well. The post war program centered around marriage, education, establishment of a home, and choice of religious affiliation. By 1964 the priorities of the Young Adult Assembly included, education and employment, racial integration, sex morality, mental health, the role of women in society, civic responsibility and political action.
At the National Young Adult Conference, in November of 1969, the group changed its name to Young Women Committed to Action and delineated its priorities as child care, housing, drugs, and continuing education. The Conference received considerable national press attention as a "Youth Rebellion" where resolutions were put forward to legalize marijuana and "hand out the Pill." Despite its well-publicized beginnings, Young Women Committed to Action was short-lived. The group was officially discontinued at Convention in 1979 due to lack of participation.
Administrative History
1949-59 Various staff members in various departments
1960-70 Consultant, Young Adult Program in the Community Division
1971-79 Youth Constituencies Unit
Scope and Content
Records related to the Young Adult work consist of sporadic minutes, general historical materials, conference files (1951-69), some Council records, a few program and project files, publications, and materials from a workshop in 1964.
As elsewhere, very few records have survived from 1970s and 1980s.
Microfilmed Records, 1906-70 only
[see Microfilmed Records Reel list]
The microfilmed records are more extensive than those in original format. Young Adult records can be found on the microfilm under:
Minutes and Reports
Young Adult Council
Subject Files
Young Adult
YWCA, Young Matrons
YWCA, YW-Wives
Original Format Records, 1948-75, n.d., 1.5 linear feet
[see Original Format Records Folder list]
The original format materials consist of a small amount of general historical materials, spotty minutes, publications, and some training materials from various iterations of Young Adult constituency from Home Women groups in the late 1940s to the Youth Constituencies Unit, 1974-75.
Related Materials
In other Subseries in this Series
Earlier records of some of the groups that were consolidated to form the Young Adult constituency are in Subseries A. Employed Women, Subseries D. Teen-Age and Younger Girls
In other Series in this Record Group
Other records about the YWCA's "family relations" work is in SERIES I. DEPARTMENT, STAFF, AND COMMITTEES.
Later records about YWCA activities related to child care services and advocacy are in SERIES III. PUBLIC ADVOCACY.
In other Record Groups
RECORD GROUP 3. NATIONAL ADMINISTRATIVE OFFICE has files related to the controversy stirred by the first Young Women Committed to Action Conference in 1969.
RECORD GROUP 4. NATIONAL CONVENTIONS AND CONFERENCES has records about Convention actions related to the Young Adult constituency.
RECORD GROUP 7. STUDENT WORK has earlier and later records of the Student constituency.
RECORD GROUP 9. PHOTOGRAPHS contains photographs of YW-Wives and Young Adults.
This Series is divided into five Subseries:
A. EMPLOYED WOMEN
B. IMMIGRATION AND FOREIGN COMMUNITIES
C. INTERRACIAL/RACIAL JUSTICE
D. TEENAGE AND YOUNGER GIRLS
E. YOUNG ADULTS
The records are open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection without any additional restrictions.
Access to audiovisual materials may first require production of research copies.
Additional Formats
A copy of the microfilmed records of the YWCA of the U.S.A. Records is available to borrow from the William Allan Neilson Library at Smith College via Interlibrary Loan.
To request the microfilm from our library you will need to submit the following information to your library's Interlibrary Loan department:
Author: Young Women's Christian Association of the U.S.A. National Board
Title: Records, 1876-1970 [microform]
WorldCat Accession Number: OCLC 57415795
Notes: "Call # 689" and reel number(s) you want to borrow
Full descriptions and reel lists of the microfilm are available online.
The YWCA of the U.S.A. donated a portion of its records to the Sophia Smith Collection in 1964 and the remainder in 2002 and 2003.
Adolescence--United States--History--20th century--Sources; African American women--Employment--History--Sources; African American women--Social conditions--History--20th century; African Americans--Civil rights--History--20th century--Sources; American Labor Education Service; Businesswomen--United States--History--20th century--Sources; Child rearing--History--Sources; Children--Health and hygiene--United States--History--20th century--Sources; Civil rights movements--United States--History--20th century--Sources; Coit, Eleanor G.; Ethnicity--United States--History--20th century; Girls--Societies and clubs--History--20th century--Sources; Immigrants--United States--History--20th century-- Sources; Indian women--North America--History--20th century--Sources; Labor laws and legislation--United States--History--20th century--Sources; Labor--United States--History--20th century--Sources; Mothers and daughters--United States--History; Race awareness--United States; Race relations--United States; Simms, Florence, 1873-1923; Social work with immigrants--United States--History--Sources; Teenage girls--United States--History; Trade and professional associations--United States--History--Sources; Women domestics--United States; Women--Employment--United States--History--20th century--Sources; Women--Employment--History--Sources; Women in the labor movement--United States--History--20th century--Sources
Record Groups
The YWCA of the USA Records are arranged as follows:
YWCA of the U.S.A. Records (main record)
RECORD GROUP 1. GENERAL AND HISTORY
RECORD GROUP 2. PREDECESSOR ORGANIZATIONS AND NATIONAL BOARD
RECORD GROUP 3. NATIONAL ADMINISTRATIVE OFFICE
RECORD GROUP 4. NATIONAL CONVENTIONS AND CONFERENCES
RECORD GROUP 5. INTERNATIONAL WORK
RECORD GROUP 6. PROGRAM
SERIES I. DEPARTMENT, STAFF, AND COMMITTEES
SERIES II. TRAINING AND PERSONNEL
SERIES III. PUBLIC ADVOCACY
SERIES IV. CONSTITUENT GROUPS
SERIES V. PROGRAM SUBJECTS
SERIES VI. PUBLICATIONS
SERIES VII. WAR WORK AND DEFENSE SERVICES
RECORD GROUP 7. STUDENT WORK
RECORD GROUP 8. COMMUNITY ASSOCIATIONS
RECORD GROUP 9. PHOTOGRAPHS
RECORD GROUP 10. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS
Artifacts
The Microfilmed Records
The Oversized Materials
This Record group forms part of the YWCA of the U.S.A. Records
- SERIES IV. CONSTITUENT GROUPS
  - Subseries A. Employed Women
    - General and History
      - General, 1900-80, n.d. (Box 467, Folder 1)
      - Thesis "Relation of Grouping, Recruiting and Induction Methods, and Program Content to the Satisfactions of Group Members: A study of the described experience of members in nine YWCA clubs for employed women (young adult) in New York City and its immediate vicinity" by Christine Maher and Lucy Waller Gilliam, Columbia University School of Social Work, 1955 (Box 467, Folder 2)
      - Ohio and West Virginia Field Federation of Industrial and Mercantile Clubs, 1916-19 (Box 467, Folder 3)
      - Department Store Workers, 1907, 1910 (Box 467, Folder 4)
      - Co-operating Committee, Central Club of Nurses: minutes and reports, 1909-12 (Box 467, Folder 5-6)
      - Younger Girls in Business and Industry (YGBI), [see also Subseries D. Teen Age and Younger Girls Programs]
        - General, 1922-28, n.d. (Box 467, Folder 7)
        - Bulletins, 1923-24 (Box 467, Folder 8)
        - Conferences, 1924-25 (Box 467, Folder 9)
      - BP and I Staff meetings, 1946-49 (Box 467, Folder 10-11)
      - Division of Community YWCAs Committee Studying the Relationship of National Councils and Assemblies to the National Board and Convention, 1947 (Box 467, Folder 12-13)
      - Ad-hoc Committee to Study the Future of Business, Professional and Industrial Council and Assembly Structure, Conferences and Program, 1948-49 (Box 467, Folder 14-17)
      - Joint Study Committee of the National Industrial Council and the Industrial Sub-Committee, 1947-49 (Box 467, Folder 18)
    - Committees
      - BP and I Subcommittees (joint meetings), 1948-50 (Box 468, Folder 1)
      - BP and I Experimentation Committee (strengthening of program with employed women)
        - General, 1948-52 (Box 468, Folder 2-7)
        - Reports: experimentation in selected communities
          - California (Box 468, Folder 8)
          - Colorado (Box 468, Folder 9)
          - Connecticut (Box 468, Folder 10)
          - Michigan (Box 468, Folder 11)
          - Mississippi (Box 468, Folder 12)
          - Missouri (Box 468, Folder 13)
          - Montana (Box 468, Folder 14)
          - New York (Box 468, Folder 15)
          - North Carolina (Box 468, Folder 16)
          - North Dakota (Box 468, Folder 17)
          - Ohio (Box 468, Folder 18)
          - Pennsylvania (Box 468, Folder 19)
          - Rhode Island (Box 468, Folder 20)
          - South Carolina (Box 468, Folder 21)
          - Tennessee and Virginia (Box 468, Folder 22)
          - Washington (Box 468, Folder 23)
          - West Virginia (Box 468, Folder 24)
        - Study Project with the National Council of Churches, "The Church in Economic Life"
          - General, 1951-52 (Box 468, Folder 25)
          - Discussion Group Reports, 1951-52 (Box 469, Folder 1)
    - Conferences and Consultations
      - Business, Professional, and Industrial
        - Summer
          - General, 1948-49 (Box 469, Folder 2)
          - Camp Gray (Industrial and YGBI), 1925-26 (Box 469, Folder 3-4)
          - Cheyney Conference for Colored Girls in Business and Industry, 1921-24 (Box 469, Folder 5)
          - Eastern Area
            - General, 1946 (Box 469, Folder 6)
            - 1944, 1946-50 (Box 469, Folder 7-12)
          - Intermountain, Alta Lodge, Alta, Utah, 1943 (Box 469, Folder 13)
          - Northwest, 1937, 1939, 1941-44, 1946 (Box 469, Folder 14-20)
          - Okoboji
            - 1926-31 (Box 469, Folder 21-26)
            - 1932-42 (Box 470, Folder 1-11)
          - Southwest, 1943-44, 1946-49 (Box 470, Folder 12-17)
          - West Central (western part of central region), 1943-44, 1946-47 (Box 470, Folder 18-21)
          - Western Area/Region/Asilomar
            - 1937-40 (Box 470, Folder 22-25)
            - 1941-42, 1946-50 (Box 471, Folder 1-7)
        - Weekend
          - General, 1946-52, n.d. (Box 471, Folder 8)
          - Miscellaneous locations, 1949-50 (Box 471, Folder 9)
          - Arizona, 1939-40 (Box 471, Folder 10)
          - Eastern, 1944-45 (Box 471, Folder 11)
          - California, northern, 1948-49 (Box 471, Folder 12)
          - Colorado and Wyoming, 1946 (Box 471, Folder 13)
          - Illinois, southern, 1944, 1949 (Box 471, Folder 14)
          - Iowa, 1936-40, 1942, 1944 (Box 471, Folder 15-21)
          - Northwest, 1936, 1938, 1940-42, 1946 (Box 471, Folder 22-26)
          - Texas-Shreveport, 1948 (Box 471, Folder 27)
          - Tri-state (Minnesota, North Dakota, South Dakota), 1947 (Box 471, Folder 28)
      - Business, Professional, Industrial and Agricultural conferences, 1948-50 (Box 471, Folder 29-31)
      - Consultation on Industrial Women Workers and Women Service Workers, Jan 1956 (Box 471, Folder 32)
      - Women in the 1960s-Their Job World: A Consultation, Feb 1960 (Box 471, Folder 33)
      - Employability Consultation, 1969 (Box 471, Folder 34)
    - Council
      - National
        - Business, Professional, and Industrial
          - Freedom of Action Project: report, 1937 (Box 472, Folder 1)
          - Joint sessions, 1947 (Box 472, Folder 2)
        - National Employed Women's Coordinating Council (NEWCC), B and P Council, and Industrial Council: minutes, 1950-51 (Box 472, Folder 3-4)
        - National Employed Women's Coordinating Council
          - General, 1949-53 (Box 472, Folder 5)
          - Audits, 1950-52 (Box 472, Folder 6)
          - Projects, 1950-51 (Box 472, Folder 7)
      - Area Councils
        - Miscellaneous, 1949-51 (Box 472, Folder 8)
        - Northwest, 1938-48 (Box 472, Folder 9-10)
        - Western, 1939-49 (Box 472, Folder 11-12)
    - Programs and Projects
      - Job-Corps YWCA Extension Residence Program/Women's Job Corps Extension Residence Program
        - General
          - 1967-72 (Box 472, Folder 13-16)
          - 1973-75, n.d. (Box 473, Folder 1)
        - Thesis: "An Abstract of the relation of met and unmet expectations to subsequent performance by trainees in the Job Corps YWCA Extension Residence Program" by Elizabeth Locke Wadsworth, NYU, School of Education, 1973 (Box 473, Folder 2-7)
        - Job Corps Center community linkages, n.d. (Box 473, Folder 8)
        - Cooperative venture with Cornell University Extension Service
          - General, 1968-69 (Box 473, Folder 9)
          - "Findings from a Consultation on Consumer and Labor Education" (Box 473, Folder 10)
        - Los Angeles Center
          - General, 1964-65 (Box 473, Folder 11-12)
          - Proposal, 1965 (Box 473, Folder 13)
        - "Monday Memo" mailings from JC-YWCA Director to staff of JC-YWCA programs, 1968-72 (Box 474, Folder 1-9)
        - The Communicator, Apr 1973-summer 1975 (Box 475, Folder 1-3)
        - Women's Training Center Staff Working Papers, circa 1969 (Box 475, Folder 4)
      - YWCA Jobs Network Project, 1979-80 (Box 475, Folder 5)
      - Demonstration Project in Employment of Rural Women, 1978-80 (Box 475, Folder 6)
    - Publications
      - Handbooks, 1936, 1948-49 (Box 475, Folder 7-9)
      - Program, 1936-45 (Box 476, Folder 1)
      - Trends in Part-Time Employment of College-Trained Women by Eva vB. Hansl, The Womans Press, 1949 (Box 476, Folder 2)
    - Studies
      - "The Responsibility of Working Women for Dependents" by Elsie Harper and Adele van A. Frank, 1938 (Box 476, Folder 3)
    - Unemployment
      - General
        - Miscellaneous, 1929-35, n.d. (Box 476, Folder 4-5)
        - Resource materials, 1930-40 (Box 476, Folder 6)
      - Committees/Commissions
        - Public Affairs, 1929-35 (Box 476, Folder 7)
        - Unemployment Council, 1929-31 (Box 476, Folder 8)
        - Emergency Committee on Unemployment, 1931 (Box 476, Folder 9)
        - Emergency Correlating Group, 1932 (Box 476, Folder 10)
      - Department/Division
        - Business and Professional Assembly, Unemployment Commission, 1931, n.d. (Box 476, Folder 11)
        - City Department, 1930-31 (Box 476, Folder 12)
        - Industrial Department, 1922-30, n.d. (Box 476, Folder 13)
        - Rural Communities Department, 1930-31 (Box 476, Folder 14)
        - Laboratory Division, 1931-35 (Box 476, Folder 15)
        - National Services Division, 1932-37 (Box 476, Folder 16)
      - Conferences and Meetings
        - General Conference on Emergency Brought About by the Unemployment Situation, Nov 1930 (Box 476, Folder 17)
        - YWCA-YMCA Joint Luncheon to Consider the Urgency of Spiritual Claims on Youth in the 1933 Mobilization for Human Needs, Oct 1933 (Box 476, Folder 18)
      - Convention resolutions, 1922-32 (Box 477, Folder 1)
      - Cooperation
        - Federal Emergency Relief Administration
          - General, 1934-35 (Box 477, Folder 2)
          - Publications and Reports, 1934 (Box 477, Folder 3)
          - Work Projects for Women, 1933-34 (Box 477, Folder 4)
        - The President's Emergency Committee on Employment
          - Correspondence and notes, 1930-31 (Box 477, Folder 5)
          - Questionnaire, 1931
            - Summaries (Box 477, Folder 6)
            - Cities over 100,000 population (Box 477, Folder 7)
            - Cities under 100,000 population (Box 477, Folder 8)
            - Towns (Box 477, Folder 9)
        - The President's Organization on Unemployment Relief, 1932 (Box 477, Folder 10)
      - Local Associations, 1930-35, n.d. (Box 477, Folder 11-14)
      - Publications
        - Bulletins on YWCA Adjustments to New Needs (Lab Division), 1933 (Box 477, Folder 15-16)
        - Community Planning for Unemployed Women Without Resources: Supplement, Aug 1932 (Box 477, Folder 17)
        - Courageous Living in Times of Crisis, 1933 (Box 477, Folder 18)
        - Out of a Job: Proposals for Unemployment Insurance by Elsie D. Harper, 1931 (Box 477, Folder 19)
        - Program for Girls Not Yet Employed, Bulletins I-VIII, 1933-34 (Box 477, Folder 20-21)
        - Series on Social Consequences of Unemployment and Mobilization of Association Resources, Bulletins II-XIII, 1930-32 (Box 478, Folder 1)
        - Suggestions for Self-Study and Suggestions for Self-Study in the Present Emergency (Lab Division), 1933 (Box 478, Folder 2)
        - A Symposium on Unemployment (for Convention 1930), 1930 (Box 478, Folder 3)
        - "Unemployment: For Leaders of Discussion Groups, A Study Outline" (aka "The Outline"), Jan 1929 (Box 478, Folder 4)
        - Unemployment's Humpty Dumpty: A Study Course in Three Lessons for the Busy Woman, 1932 (Box 478, Folder 5)
      - Transient and Homeless
        - General, 1933-41 (Box 478, Folder 6)
        - Local Associations report, 1933 (Box 478, Folder 7)
        - National Committee on Care of Transient and Homeless, 1932-38, n.d. (Box 478, Folder 8)
        - Report on housing for indigent and unattached women, circa 1937 (Box 478, Folder 9)
        - Resource materials, 1931-38, n.d. (Box 478, Folder 10)
    - Business and Professional Women
      - General and History
        - General, 1919-84, n.d. (Box 479, Folder 1-3)
        - Aims and purpose, 1924-31, n.d. (Box 479, Folder 4)
        - Reports
          - Biennial, 1928-29, 1937-39, 1940-44 (Box 479, Folder 5)
          - Secretary, 1918-20 (Box 479, Folder 6)
        - Secretary's job analysis, 1925-31, n.d. (Box 479, Folder 7)
        - Staff meeting minutes, 1944-47 (Box 479, Folder 8)
      - Committees
        - B and P Women's Committee: minutes, 1919-20 (Box 479, Folder 9)
        - National B and P Committee: minutes, 1925 (Box 479, Folder 10)
        - Department Committee: minutes, 1927-29 (Box 479, Folder 11)
        - National B and P Committee/Subcommittee: minutes, 1937-50 (Box 479, Folder 12-15)
      - Conferences
        - General, 1918-46 (Box 479, Folder 16)
        - Summer
          - Asilomar, 1930-36 (Box 479, Folder 17-18)
          - Camp Gray, 1926-31 (Box 479, Folder 19-22)
          - East Central Area, Forest Beach Camp, 1940-44, 1946-50 (Box 480, Folder 1-11)
          - Eastern Region (Maqua and 'Kiski' Areas)
            - Maqua, 1929 (Box 480, Folder 12)
            - Summit Lake Camp, 1932-33, 1935 (Box 480, Folder 13-15)
            - Wells College
              - 1936-38 (Box 480, Folder 16-18)
              - 1939, 1941 (Box 481, Folder 1-2)
            - Mt. Hermon School, 1940 (Box 481, Folder 3)
            - Wellesley College, 1942 (Box 481, Folder 4)
          - Estes Park (Colorado), 1928-29 (Box 481, Folder 5)
          - Forest Beach Camp, 1933-38 (Box 481, Folder 6-9)
          - Great Lakes Region Leadership Conference, Mary Eells Camp, 1932 (Box 481, Folder 10)
          - Kiski Business Girls, Kiskiminetas Springs School, 1928-31 (Box 481, Folder 11)
          - Southern Business Girls/Southern Area Business and Professional
            - Blue Ridge, North Carolina, 1929-30 (Box 481, Folder 12-13)
            - Camp Nakanawa, Tennessee, 1931-34 (Box 481, Folder 14-17)
            - Camp Chelan, Indiana, 1935-36 (Box 481, Folder 18-19)
            - Camp Merrie-Woode, N. Carolina
              - 1937-40 (Box 481, Folder 20-23)
              - 1941-43 (Box 482, Folder 1-3)
            - Camp Highland Lake, N. Carolina, 1944, 1946 (Box 482, Folder 4-5)
            - Camp Chelan, Indiana, 1947, 1949 (Box 482, Folder 6-7)
            - Gay Valley Camp, North Carolina, 1950 (Box 482, Folder 8)
          - Southwest Area, Camp Mirror Lake, 1939-42 (Box 482, Folder 9-12)
          - Southwest Leadership, Glen Rose, Texas, 1936-37 (Box 482, Folder 13-14)
        - Weekend (fall, mid-winter, mid-year)
          - Arizona, New Mexico, and West Texas, 1946 (Box 482, Folder 15)
          - Arkansas and Monroe, Louisiana, 1935-40, 1948 (Box 482, Folder 16)
          - California, northern, 1937-45 (Box 482, Folder 17)
          - California, southern, 1939-40 (Box 482, Folder 18)
          - Carolinas, 1935-46 (Box 482, Folder 19-20)
          - Colorado-Wyoming, 1926, 1937-45 (Box 482, Folder 21)
          - Florida, 1935-40 (Box 482, Folder 22)
          - Illinois, southern, 1936-38, 1946 (Box 482, Folder 23-24)
          - Indiana, northern, 1935, 1940 (Box 483, Folder 1)
          - Indiana, southern, 1936-38 (Box 483, Folder 2)
          - Inland Empire (Idaho, Utah, Washington), 1938-40, 1947 (Box 483, Folder 3)
          - Kansas and Missouri, 1935-43 (Box 483, Folder 4-5)
          - Kentucky-Tennessee, 1935-40 (Box 483, Folder 6)
          - Michigan, 1938-44 (Box 483, Folder 7)
          - Middle Atlantic, 1935-40, 1949 (Box 483, Folder 8-9)
          - New England, northern, 1930-41 (Box 483, Folder 10-12)
          - New England, southern, 1935-46 (Box 483, Folder 13)
          - New Jersey, 1936-46 (Box 483, Folder 14-15)
          - New York, eastern, 1935-39 (Box 483, Folder 16)
          - New York, western, 1936-40, 1950 (Box 483, Folder 17)
          - Ohio, northern, 1936-48 (Box 483, Folder 18-19)
          - Ohio, southern, 1934-46 (Box 483, Folder 20)
          - Oklahoma, 1936-40 (Box 484, Folder 1-2)
          - Pennsylvania, western, 1938 (Box 484, Folder 3)
          - Texas-Shreveport, 1935-41, 1944-45 (Box 484, Folder 4-8)
          - Tri-state Area (Alabama, Louisiana, Mississippi), 1935-47 (Box 484, Folder 9)
          - Tri-state Area (Minnesota, N. and S. Dakota), 1937-40 (Box 484, Folder 10-12)
          - Tri-state Area (Ohio, Pennsylvania, West Virginia), 1937 (Box 484, Folder 13)
          - Virginia, 1935-37 (Box 484, Folder 14)
          - West Virginia, 1937-39 (Box 484, Folder 15)
          - Wisconsin and Northern Illinois, 1936-45 (Box 484, Folder 16)
      - Council
        - Handbooks, c. 1942, 1946 (Box 484, Folder 17)
        - National Council
          - General, 1922-48 (Box 484, Folder 18)
          - Financial, 1926-30, 1940-50 (Box 484, Folder 19)
          - Meetings
            - 1925-29 (Box 484, Folder 20)
            - 1931-49 (Box 485, Folder 1-4)